Now, let's learn about the breadth first search algorithm.
Consider the graph of five vertices is here.
Zero, one, two, three and four.
So we have the five vertices here.
That river also mean visiting all nodes of graph breadth, first traversal or breadth.
First search is a recursive algorithm for searching all the vertices of a graph or the tree data structure.
This it's the same mission, the same goal of all of the previously career of the previous search algorithm
that we have learned about that DFS.
It is visiting all the node, but here we have the different concept.
OK, so.
We have the visited notes, the standard VFX breadth first algorithm search algorithm implementation
put each vertex of the graph into one of the two categories they're visited and none visited.
The purpose of algorithm is to mark each vertex as visited while avoiding the cycles, and the algorithm
works as follows Start by putting anyone on the on off the graphs vertices at the back of the queue
and then take the front item of the queue and add it to their visited list, then create a list of that
vertex.
Adjacent nodes add the ones which are not in the visited list to the back of the queue and keep repeating
these steps until the queue is empty.
The graph must or might have two different disconnected parts, so make sure that we cover every vertex.
We can also run the BFC algorithm on every note.
OK, so let's take an example here.
We have zero.
We start from zero if we are following the numerical value zero.
The note is a visited note is the vertex.
OK, so the vertex or the starting point is always added directly and automatically to the visited notes.
Then from zero, we can go to one at the same level, we can go to two and in the same level we can
go to three.
So this is that this is the breadth first search algorithm.
We moved to that to zero, the first vertex.
And from this vertex, what are the possibilities to the jaw a to go and make one step forward, not
moving like too forward or do any other elements?
So we go, we are going or we can go to zero if you are standing on zero so we can go to one, two and
three.
These are plotted directly in a numerical order or in the chronological order or in the alphabetical
order if you had.
This depends on the data types that you are dealing with.
OK.
Since we have finished zero, we move now to one, then one, we cannot go to any where from it.
We can also go to two just on the one step two to two US-VISIT, so we can put it from two.
We go two, from one, we go to do it, we can go to any nodes, we can go to zero, we can go to one
and we can go to four.
Zero and one have been added previously and visited.
So we are going to add four to that, to this example and this visit the notes.
OK.
So this is the breadth first search algorithm that we are going to implement it in to see.
Let's take an example.
Another example?
In the next video.
So let me show you the codes later on, and we are going to implement it into the exercise number 90
in Java.
So this is the breadth first search algorithm BFC.
I hope you understand it.
It's very simple.
Just going from the note that you are.
And we make one step one visit.
OK, so we can make here one visit, one visit, not two visits like zero, two and two or four.
We just go one one visit one link.
OK.